Where's the bigger one?
でっかいやつは
うん 羽川さんに見てもらってる
Hanekawa-san's looking after her.
Then tell me the details.
じゃ 詳しいことを教えてもらおうか
うん それはいいけれど
Sure, okay.
その前に一つだけ約束してくれる
But will you promise me something first?
条件を出せる立場かよ
Are you in a position to make demands?
Sure, I am. I'm your little sister.
私の立場は妹だから出せる
僕の立場は兄だから断る
And I'm your big brother, so I can refuse them.
Fine. Forget it.
分かった 諦める
ちなみに どんな条件を出すつもりだったんだ
By the way, what were you going to ask me to do?
Not to get mad at Karen-chan.
火憐ちゃんを怒らないであげてって
No.
駄目だ
You can be mad at me,
私は怒られてもいいけど 火憐ちゃんは怒らないであげてって
but don't get mad at Karen-chan.
I'm getting mad at both of you.
両方怒る
火憐ちゃんを怒ってもいいけど 私のことは怒らないで
You can be mad at Karen-chan,
but please don't get mad at me.
I'm already mad.
つーかもう怒ってんだよ さっさと話して楽になれ
So start talking and get it off your chest.
むう 格好いいこと言っちゃって
You think you're so cool.
羽川さんの前では怒らないって約束した癖に
You promised you wouldn't get mad
when Hanekawa-san was around.
お兄ちゃんはさ 何か後悔してることってある
Do you have any regrets, Onii-chan?
Regrets?
後悔 んなもんいつだってしてる
Of course I do.
Doesn't everyone?
しない人間なんかいるのかよ
Well, I don't know...
なんて言うのかな 私は後悔ってあんまりしない方なんだけど
I guess I'm not the type to regret things.
I bet.
だろうな お前ら姉妹はそんな感じだ
You two sisters are like that.
だけど だからこそ
But that means that sometimes,
I regret that I didn't regret something
何であのとき後悔しておかなかったのかなあって
when I should have.
後悔することはあるんだよね
Not that it matters.
ま いいんだけど
I guess you really want to be strangled...
どうやら 首を絞められたいようだな
No, that's not it...
あ いや そういうわけじゃなく
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Then get to the point.
それならさっさと本題に入れ
そうだお兄ちゃん いいこと教えてあげるよ
I know, Onii-chan...
I'll tell you something cool.
いいこと
Something cool?
You know how I always say I'm "platinum" mad?
私の口癖の「プラチナむかつく」のことなんだけど
あれ 元々は「プチむかつく」からの変化だから
It was originally "pretty" mad.
プラチナって言葉から連想されるほど強くむかついてるわけじゃないの
To make it sound like I'm not that mad,
the word "platinum" came to mind.
I've never heard you say "platinum" mad.
お前の口癖が「プラチナむかつく」だってことが初耳だ
How come you don't know?
何で知らないのよ プラチナむかつく
I'm platinum mad!
明らかに激怒してんじゃねえか
You're clearly extremely upset!
And stop trying to cleverly change the subject.
つーか 巧妙に話を逸らそうとするな
じゃあお兄ちゃん その前になにか
Okay, Onii-chan.
Then why don't you tell me something you regret?
お兄ちゃんが後悔した時の話とかしてくれない
お兄ちゃんの後悔エピソード 聞きたいな
I want to hear it.
Just telling you straight out would be kind of upsetting.
普通に話すのは何だか悔しいし
お互いに秘密を打ち明け合うみたいにできないかな
So we could share secrets or something, maybe.
Like we were on a school trip or something!
修学旅行の夜みたく
馬鹿が
Idiot...
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Still, something I regret, huh?
つっても 僕の後悔エピソードっつってもな
It's hard to come up with something
直感的に訊かれると 当惑する
now that I think about it.
Perhaps something that's just a little embarrassing.
だから ちょっと恥ずかしい感じの話だよ
Like... Oh...
そう...たとえば
Why don't you have any friends?
お兄ちゃんにはどうして友達がいないのか とか
I have friends now!
今はいる
Do you?
そうなの 何人
How many?
何人だと 聞いて驚け
How many, you say?
Let me tell you...
Five!
五人
Wow, that seriously scared me.
いや マジで驚いた
お兄ちゃん可哀想 きっとそのまま寂しく死んでいくんだね
Poor Onii-chan...
You're going to die of loneliness!
Don't be so mean to your brother!
実の兄に酷いことを言うな
Anyway, I have some now,
で 今はともかく
but you're asking why I didn't have any before.
一時期僕にはどうして友達がいなかったのかって話だけどな
Well, here's what I used to think.
そうだな 僕は昔こんな風に思っていたんだ
If you make friends, that means your human hardness—
友達を作ると人間強度が...
No, I've already heard enough embarrassing stuff.
いや 十分に恥ずかしい話はもう聞けたのでいいよ
変なことを訊いてごめんなさい
I'm sorry I asked.
Don't apologize yet!
まだ謝るな 僕はまだ恥ずかしい話なんてしていない
I haven't said anything embarrassing!
Stop it, Onii-chan!
やめてお兄ちゃんもういいの それ以上傷口を広げなくてもいいの
That's enough!
You needn't reopen the wounds anymore!
もうやめて もう終わったんだよ
Stop it... It's over!
It's not over!
終わってねえ
Araragi-kun, I can hear you from the second floor!
阿良々木くん ちょっと二階まで声が響いてるんだけど
And I can hear you talking about something
それも恐らくは雑談と思われる会話の声が響いてるんだけど
that really doesn't sound too important.
Could you be a little quieter?
もうちょっと静かに喋れないものなの
Yeah, sorry.
ああ 悪い 気を付ける
I'll be more care...
AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA
UUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUU
GGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGGG
HHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHH
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
Karen Bee Part 5
Episode 5
Type Font Used HGP Minchou B
Let's talk about Araragi Karen for a while.
暫くは阿良々木火憐の話
Of course, this is just based on what
と言っても 僕が羽川と月火の話を聞き
I heard from Tsukihi and Hanekawa.
それを統合しての場面回想なので
So it may differ slightly from what happened.
実際とは少し違うのかもしれないけれど
Back-up Vocals
Artist's Image
Repeat
Stop
Live Version
Duet
Artist
New Song
Recall
Song Title
Sort
Welcome, young lady.
ようこそお嬢さん 俺は貝木
My name is Kaiki.
Kaichou 【快著】 - A splendid work of literature
Kaichou 【開帳】  - ➀ unveiling of a Buddhist statue or icon. ➁ A gambler's position
Kaichou 【諧調】 - Unity, Concord, Euphony, Harmony, Melody
Gaichou 【害鳥】 - vermin, injurious bird
Kaichin 【開陳】 - stating, to express one's opinion or thought
Kaitsuu 【開通】 - Open, Opening where one can pass through (i.e. a road)
Kaidzuka 【貝塚】 - Shell mound, especially from the Stone Age
Kaitsuke 【買い付け】 - Buying, the act of purchasing
Kaitsuburi 【鳰掻】 - Little grebe, A water bird
Kaitsumamu 【掻い摘む】 - summarize
Kaitei 【買い手】 - someone who purchases, buyer
Kaitei 【改 定】 - reform, revision
Kaiteki 【快適】 - comfortable, at ease
Kaitetsu 【塊鐵】 - iron lump, iron ore
"Kai," like a mound of clamshells. "Ki," like a dead tree.
貝塚の貝に 枯れ木の木だ
Kare-eda 【枯れ枝】 -  A dead branch, void as well of withered leaves
Kare-obana 【枯尾華】 - 「a collection written by Kikaku alongside "Bashou's Last Days" dedicated to Matsuo Bashou」
Kare-gashi 【彼某】 -  a term for someone whom one is not familiar with
Kare-gata 【離方】 -  Cessation on one's part 「i.e. of a mutual relationship with someone」
Kare-gare 【枯枯】 -  The withering or wilting of vegetation
Kare-ki 【枯れ木】 -  Dry wood, Dead tree
Ga-reki 【瓦礫】 -  Rubble (i.e. a rock fragment)
Kareki-gaku 【花暦學】 -  "The Study of Flower Almanacs"
What's your name?
お前の名前を聞こうか
Araragi Karen.
阿良々木火憐だ
こざと偏に可能性の可 良い良い それに若木の木
The "kozato" radical with the kanji for possibility.
Araragi
Karen
"It is good."
Araragi
Karen
And "ki," like a young tree.
Araragi
Karen
And my given name means "to admire the flame."
火を憐れむで 火憐だ
Araragi
Karen
Karen.
An excellent name.
いい名だな 親に感謝しておけ
Be grateful to your parents.
Araragi
Karen
So, which are you?
それでお前はどちらだ
Do you want to learn a spell?
「おまじない」を教えてほしいのか
Or have one undone?
それとも「おまじない」を解いてほしいのか
The former is 10,000 yen.
前者なら一万 後者なら二万だ
The latter, 20,000.
Neither.
どちらでもねえ あんたを殴りに来た
I've come here to punch you!
殴りに来た
To punch me?
ほう つまり俺を嘘のメールで呼び出し罠にはめたということか
So the message you sent me was fake,
and this is a trap.
なるほど 見事な手際だ
I see.
Well done.
Of course, I don't believe that
もっとも お前の手柄とは思えないな
you were the one who did it.
I can't imagine a simpleton like you
お前のような短絡的な人間が 俺の地点まで辿り着けるとは思えない
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
being able to reach me.
Not many people could.
そうはいないはずなんだ
こうして俺と対面できるところまで到着するなどやや常識を逸している
Only someone who's a touch abnormal
could get this far.
あんたのやってることはすげー迷惑なんだ
What you're doing is a giant pain in the butt.
いちいち説明しなくても分かるよな
You don't need me to explain, do you?
A pain?
何が迷惑だ 俺はお前達の望んだものを売渡しているだけだぞ
I'm giving you kids what you want.
How you use it is your responsibility.
その後は自己責任だろう
Our responsibility?
自己責任
何が自己責任だ ふざけんな
How is it our responsibility?
How dare you?!
人間関係を引っ掻き回すようなことばかりしやがって
You're ruining people's relationships...
どういうつもりなんだよ
What are you thinking?
What am I thinking?
どういうつもりか 深い問いだな
Quite a deep question.
Unfortunately, I'll have to respond with a shallow answer.
しかし残念なことに俺は深い問いに対して浅い答えを返すことになる
それは勿論 金のためだ
I'm doing it for the money, naturally.
M-Money?
か...金
Akasegawa
Bank of Fraud
Fraud
世の中と言うのは金が全てだからな
Money makes the world go round.
10,000
Yen
Issued by the
Fraud Bank
10,000
I suppose you've come here out of
お前はどうやらくだらん正義感でここに来たようだが
Akasegawa
Bank of Fraud
Fraud
10,000
Yen
Issued by the
Fraud Bank
some primitive sense of justice.
惜しいことをしたものだ
その行為 依頼人から十万は取れる
But that was a mistake.
You could have earned 100,000 yen for this.
今回の件からお前が得るべき教訓は ただ働きは割に合わないだ
The lesson for you here is that working for free
isn't worth it.
依頼人なんているか
No one hired me!
And I'm not here because I was asked to come.
あたしは誰かに頼まれてこんなことをしているわけじゃない
Akasegawa
10,000
Yen
Bank of Fraud
Fraud
Issued by the
Fraud Bank
そうか 誰かに頼まれておくべきだったな
I see...
Then you should have had someone ask you.
頼まれたとしても 金なんかいらない
Even if someone had, I wouldn't have taken their money!
Such childish impertinence...
若いな 決して羨ましいとは思わないが
I'm not at all jealous, though.
What's wrong?
どうしだ 震えているぞ 阿良々木
You're shaking, Araragi.
Akasegawa
10,000
Yen
Bank of Fraud
Fraud
Issued by the
Fraud Bank
震えてなんかいねえ
I'm not shaking...
Araragi, you've heard what I wanted.
阿良々木 お前は俺の目的を訊いたな 今度はお前の番だ
Now it's your turn.
What do you want?
お前の目的は何なのだ
I told you already.
もう言ったろ あんたを殴りに来たんだ
I came here to punch you!
Just to punch me?
殴るだけか
I'll kick you too!
蹴りもする
Violence, then?
暴力か
武力だ そしてあたしはあんたのやっていることをやめさせる
Force!
And I'll make you stop this.
Selling this crap to middle schoolers?
中学生相手に阿漕な商売しやがって 何考えてんだ
What are you thinking?
それでも大人か
And you call yourself an adult?!
I am indeed an adult.
これでも大人だ
And of course I'm selling it to them...
それに阿漕な商売になるのは当たり前だ
I'm a con man, after all.
俺は詐欺師だからな
Isn't it embarrassing to sell spells to middle schoolers?
中学生相手に 恥ずかしくないのか
Not at all.
別に 子供が相手だから騙しやすい それだけのことだ
Children are simple to fool.
That's all.
しかし阿良々木よ 俺のやっていることをやめさせたければ
But, Araragi, if you want to stop me,
殴るのも蹴るのもとりあえずは無駄だな
punches and kicks are useless.
The fastest way would be to bring money.
それより金をもってくるのが手っ取り早い
My target for this little business is 3,000,000 yen.
この件に関する俺の目標額は三百万だ
3,000,000 Yen
I've waited over two months for it to take root.
根を張るまでに二か月以上かけている
Any less, and it wouldn't be worth my time.
最低でもそれくらいは儲けないと割に合わない
あんた それでも人間かよ
And you call yourself human?
Unfortunately, I am very much human.
生憎だが これでも人間だよ
I'm willing to sacrifice my life to protect
大切なものを命を賭して守りたいと思う ただの人間だ
what's dear to me.
お前は善行を積むことで心を満たし
Just as you fill your heart through good deeds,
俺は悪行を積むことで貯金通帳を満たす
I fill my bank account with evil ones.
Is there really a difference?
そこにどれほの違いがある
A-A difference?
違いって
そう 違いなどない
No, there's no difference at all.
Your activities may make someone happier.
お前はお前の行為によって誰かを幸せにするかもしれない
But the same is true
しかしそれは
if I take the money I've earned and use it
俺が稼いだ金を浪費して資本主義経済を潤すのと何ら変わりがないのだ
to grease the gears of a capitalist economy.
今回の件からお前がえるべき教訓は
The lesson for you here is that
just as any problem can be solved by being right,
正義で解決しないことがないよう
金で解決しないこともないということだ
every problem can also be solved with money.
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
The same is true of my victims, no?
俺の被害に遭った連中にしてもそうだろう
They paid me in money.
連中は俺に金を払った
それは取引の対価として金を認めたということだ
This means that they recognized
money as an object of value.
Red Scene
Animation Number "None"
Is the same not true of you?
お前だってそうだろう 阿良々木
Or did you not pay
それともお前は そのジャージを買うとき金を払わなかったのか
in money when you bought that jacket?
D-Don't talk about my jacket!
ジャ...ジャージのことだけは言うな
Just give me your answer.
いいから結論を出せ
あたしに殴られたいのか それとも
Do you want to be punched?
Or...
殴られたくはない 蹴られたくもないな
I don't want to be punched.
Nor do I want to be kicked.
I dislike pain.
痛いのは嫌いだ
So...
だから お前には蜂をプレゼントしよう
Here is a present for you. A bee.
It's working quite well.
効果覿面だな
随分と思い込みの激しいタイプと見える
You must have an active imagination.
The lesson for you here is to assume
今回の件からお前が得るべき教訓は
人を見たら詐欺師と思えと言うことだ
that any person you see is a con man.
Learn to doubt others.
人を疑うということを少しは憶えるのだな
俺が許しを請うとでも思ったのか
Did you think I would beg for forgiveness?
Then you're just a fool.
だとすれば愚かだ 俺を改心させたくば金を積め
If you want me to have a change of heart,
bring some cash.
一千万円から議論してやろう
I'd be willing to discuss it for 10,000,000 yen.
What did you do?
な...何をした あたしに何をした
What did you do to me?!
悪いことだよ
Something bad.
Of course, nothing is free.
勿論有料だ 金はもらう
I'll take money for it.
4,000 yen? I suppose that will do.
四千円か まあいいだろう さっきの話の分はサービスしておく
I'll throw in our little chat as a bonus.
I suppose I can leave some change for train fare home...
電車代として小銭くらいは残しておく...
Oh, you already have a ticket.
何だ 定期券があるのか
Then you won't need this change.
ならば小銭は不要だな
In a moment, the poison will take hold,
少しすれば毒が定着し動けるようにはなる
and you'll be able to move.
I recommend using a cell phone to call for help.
携帯を使って助けを呼ぶことを勧めるよ
俺はその間にとんずらするとしよう
In the meantime I'll make my escape.
Of course, I'll continue what I'm doing.
勿論 商売は続けさせてもらうが
But from now on, I'll avoid meeting customers directly.
しかし 直接顧客と会うのはこれからは避けたほうがよさそうだな
An excellent lesson...
いい教訓になった
ではさらばだ
Farewell.
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Araragi-kun, are you upset?
阿良々木君 怒ってる
何を
About what?
何て言うか 犯人を突き止めたのは私なんだし
Well, you know...
I was the one who tracked him down.
火憐ちゃんがあんなことになっちゃったこと
Are you mad about what happened to Karen-chan?
怒ってる
怒ってるわけじゃないけれど
I wouldn't say I'm mad.
でもあのファイヤーシスターズに協力するなら
But I'd like to say that if you were going to
僕にも教えて欲しかったっていう文句は言いたいね
help the Fire Sisters, you should have told me.
But wouldn't you have gotten mad?
だって そのときこそ阿良々木君は怒るでしょ
それに 私が個人的に火憐ちゃんや月火ちゃんと友達になるのは自由じゃない
And if I decide I want to be friends with Karen-chan and Tsukihi-chan,
isn't it my choice?
自由だな
It is your choice.
Yup.
だね
But as an apology for not telling you
でも せっかくだから
阿良々木君には火憐ちゃんと月火ちゃんのことを黙っていたお詫びとして
about Karen-chan and Tsukihi-chan,
you can have this ticket!
このチケットをあげましょう
What's this?
なにこれ
This ticket entitles you to touch my breasts
いつでも好きなときに好きなだけ私の胸に触っていいチケット
whenever you like for as long as you want.
It's yours.
あげる
Seriously?
マジでっ
うん マジだよ
Seriously.
その代わり使ったら一生軽蔑するけど
But if you use it, I'll hate you forever.
Then it's useless!
意味ねえー！
まあ 私のことはともかくとしてさ
Well, putting that aside,
don't be too mean to Karen-chan and Tsukihi-chan.
阿良々木君
あんまり火憐ちゃんと月火ちゃんをいじめないであげてね
大丈夫だよ そっちも心配するな
It's fine.
Don't worry about it.
I realize they aren't just doing it for fun.
あいつらがただのわがままでやってんじゃないことくらいわかってる
I know we talked about this before...
そうなんだよね
同属嫌悪の話じゃないけど あの子達さ
やっぱ似てるんだよ 阿良々木君と
But still, they are similar to you.
外見の話か
They resemble me?
外見じゃなくて中身の話だよ
Not on the outside, on the inside.
ま 私もあんまり人のこと言えないけどね
I guess I'm not one to talk, though.
そりゃそうだ
That's sure true.
もっとも 僕達兄妹とお前とじゃあ やっぱ違うけどな
Of course, your family and mine are different.
Oshino-san...
忍野さん
忍野さん 今頃どうしてるかなあ
What's Oshino-san up to right now?
さあ
I don't know.
でもきっとどこかで 僕達のことを見守ってくれているさ
But he's watching over us from somewhere.
He'll probably just fix
whatever's wrong with Karen-chan.
あいつならきっと 火憐ちゃんのこととか
あっさり解決しちゃうんだろうな
囲い火蜂ってのも
From what Shinobu said, the wreathe-fire bee
忍に聞く限りは随分レベルの低い怪異みたいだし
is a very low-level monster.
忍ちゃん 囲い火蜂
Shinobu-chan?
Wreathe-fire bee?
ふうん 囲い火蜂ね
A wreathe-fire bee, huh?
でも 阿良々木君が忍ちゃんと和解したってのはいい話だね
But I'm glad to see you've made up with Shinobu-chan.
I'm not upset about it, but...
悪い話ではないけどな
Well, the reason Oshino-san left was
まあ 忍野さんがこの町から出て行ったのも
because he thought he could leave Shinobu-chan to you, right?
阿良々木君に忍ちゃんを任せられると判断したからだもんね
本当なら 文化祭の直後に和解しててもおかしくなかったくらいだもん
Really, it would've made sense if you'd reconciled
just after the culture fair.
だとすると 随分時間をかけてしまったもんだ
I guess that means it's taken a long time.
You could say I've been slacking on the job.
僕の怠慢と言っていいな
阿良々木君は怠慢なんてしてないよ
You haven't been slacking at all.
I know that very well.
それは私がよく知ってる
You know everything, don't you?
お前は何でも知ってるな
何でもは知らないわよ
I don't know everything.
知ってることだけ
I just know what I know.
The real problem in fighting
comes after you've made up.
喧嘩っていうのは和解してからが大変なんだから
その辺の心得違いをしないでね
Keep that in mind.
I can go the rest of the way by myself.
じゃ この辺でいいや
Take my bike.
自転車乗ってけよ 貸しとくから
I'll lend it to you.
You're sure?
いいの 遠慮しないけど
I'll take it, I guess.
Okay. Then thanks.
じゃ ありがたく借りてあげましょう
I'll give it back tomorrow.
明日返すね
Yeah.
おう
Get this solved tonight.
今日中に解決しときなさいよ
You have to start studying again tomorrow.
阿良々木君は明日からまた
受験勉強をやらなきゃいけないんだから
It's good that you're being a brother,
兄としての立場もいいけど
高校生としての本分を見失わないでね
but don't forget that you're a high school student too!
ああ 大げさだよ 兄ちゃん
You're making too big a deal out of this, Nii-chan.
だから兄ちゃんには黙ってたかったのに
That's why I didn't want to tell you.
みんな口軽過ぎ
People should keep their mouths shut.
熱くらいで心配し過ぎだっつーの
It's just a fever.
Shut up.
うるせえ 病人は黙って言うこと聞いてろ
You're sick, so shut up and do what I say.
Want to eat something?
なんか食べたいか 桃缶とか
Canned peaches?
I'm not hungry.
食欲皆無
そうかよ
I see.
I'm gonna let down your hair.
髪 ほどくぞ
I want to take a bath.
風呂入りてえ 汗がきもい
This sweat feels awful.
Your hair.
髪
Go ahead.
ご自由に
A bath isn't happening,
風呂は無理だけど
身体を拭くくらいならしてやるぞ
but I'll wipe down your body.
ああ お願いするわ
Thanks.
不本意ながら
Not that I like it.
そっか
Right.
じゃあまあ 服脱いでろ
Then take off your clothes.
C
Range
Sterilize
Deodorize
Oven
Grill
Steam
Heated
Menu  Temperature  Time
Heat
Healthy
Manual
Automatic
Water
Finish
Favorite
Settings
Presets
Set
Manual
Cancel
おい 脱いでろって言ったろ
Hey, I said to take off your clothes.
ごめん 兄ちゃん
Sorry, Nii-chan.
だりい 脱がせれ
I'm tired...
Take my clothes off.
拭けれ そして着せれ
Wipe me down.
Put them back on.
Why, you...
てめえ
My brother has seen
me completely in the nude,
how embarrassing.
Karen
My brother has seen
me completely in the nude,
how embarrassing.
Karen
My brother has seen
兄ちゃんに 裸見られて 恥ずかしい
me completely in the nude, how embarrassing.
Why is it a haiku?
何で俳句調なんだよ
Since I'm embarrassed!
照れ隠し
You dance around half naked after your baths.
風呂上り半裸で踊ってる奴が何言ってんだ
I don't want to hear it.
踊ってる言うな
I'm not dancing!
あれはエアロビクスだ
It's aerobics!
背中を拭く 裏返れ
I'll wipe down your back.
Turn over.
Too lazy.
めんどい 裏返せ
Turn me over.
Damn it...
くっそう
不覚だよなあ こういうの
I screwed this up.
You don't need to tell me that strength is more important than being right.
兄ちゃんに言われなくとも
正しさよりも強さが大切なことくらいわかってるよ
でも 急に強くはなれないじゃん
But you can't get strong all of a sudden.
However,
だからって 強くなるまでは目の前で起きてる不正を見逃す
that doesn't mean you can just ignore all the bad stuff you see
until you are strong.
なんてことはできないし
あたしに流れる正義の血が 悪を許さないんだよ
The blood of justice flows through me,
and it tells me to punish evil.
You just like punching people.
お前は暴れたいだけだよ 僕から見りゃ
That's what I think.
I'm sure it all looks like a game to you.
そりゃ 兄ちゃんから見ればごっこなんだろうけどさ
But Kaiki...
でもさ 貝木
貝木泥舟
Kaiki Deishuu...
そいつがどうして中学生の間で
Tsukihi-chan already told you
why he was spreading those weird spells and curses
あんな変なオカルトみたいなおまじない...呪いをはやらせたか
around the middle schools, right?
兄ちゃんももう月火ちゃんから聞いたんだろ
そう お金のためだってさ
That's right... It was for money.
He spread hatred...
悪意を煽って 不安を煽って そこに付け込んで
Fear...
And then he took advantage of it,
実際には何もしないままに
by taking money without actually doing anything.
お金をむしりとるんだ
恥ずかしくないのかって責めたら
And when I asked him if he wasn't ashamed,
and he said this.
貝木はあたしに言ったぞ
Without a trace of shame, he said,
悪びれることなく言ったぞ
"Children are easier to fool."
子供が相手だから騙しやすいって
Easier to fool...
騙しやすい...
月火ちゃんの友達の千石って子
Tsukihi-chan's friend... Sengoku, was it?
あの子はなんだかすんげえ口が重かったけど
She didn't really want to talk about it,
まあ何にしても
but whatever happened, you saved her, didn't you?
兄ちゃんに助けられたらしいじゃん
でも そんなの幸運な例でさ
But she was one of the lucky ones.
Some kids went to Kaiki for help,
貝木が噂の発信源だとも知らないで貝木に助けを求めて
not knowing he was the source of the rumors.
要求されたお金を払うために
And when they tried to get their money back,
万引きして捕まった子だっている
he demanded they be arrested for shoplifting first.
兄ちゃんならそんなの 許せるのか
Could you have let that happen?
そんな子を前にして
Would you have looked them in the eye and said,
自分はまだ強くないから何もしないって
"I'm not strong yet, so I won't do anything"?
そんな台詞を言えるのかよ
あいつは金が全てだって言ったぞ
He told me money is everything.
I didn't think anyone like that existed outside of a manga.
あんな漫画みたいな台詞
本当に言う奴がいるとは思わなかった
I mean, money is important.
だって 確かに金は大事だけど
But aren't there other things that matter too?
他にも大切なもんがあるはずだろう
LOVE
Talent
Sold Out
First Love
LOVE
Now
On Sale
LOVE
Tax
included
Like love!
愛とか
うわあ 意見がかぶった
Our opinions overlapped.
Money isn't everything.
金は全てじゃない
It's just almost everything!
ほとんどだ
Okay, maybe not.
いや あんまりかぶってないか
兄ちゃん あたしや月火ちゃんはマジでやってんだよ
Nii-chan, Tsukihi-chan and I are serious about this.
これに懲りたりなんかしねえ
We won't stop here.
もしもこの先に これと同じことがあったら
If this happens again, we'll do the same thing.
絶対同じことをする
This time the outcome may be a loss.
あたしは結果的に負けたけど
精神的には負けてねえ
But I didn't lose mentally.
And next time, I'll win.
そして次は勝つ
I'll keep it up until I win.
勝つまでやる
I'll try even if I don't win.
勝てなくともやる
大事なのは 結果じゃないはずだろ 兄ちゃん
The outcome isn't all that's important. Right, Nii-chan?
試合に負けても勝負に勝つって奴か
Lose the match, but win the game, huh?
That's not something I'd expect to hear from a martial artist.
武道に身を置く奴の言うこととは思えないな
試合に負けて 勝負にも負けて
You can lose the match and the game,
それでも 自分に負けなきゃ 負けじゃねえ
but if you don't lose to yourself, it isn't a loss.
それがあたしの武道なんだよ
That's my way.
But as long as you stay like that,
だけど お前がそういう姿勢でいる限り
迷惑するのは周りなんだぜ
those around you will suffer.
そんなことだから
That's why you'll never grow up.
お前はいつまでたっても 大人になれねえんだよ
I'm already grown up.
あたしはもう大人だ
Look at these boobs!
見ろこのおっぱい
Not even half Hanekawa's size.
羽川の半分もない それがどうした
What of it?
え 翼さんってそんななの
Tsubasa-san is that big?
She's the real thing.
あれが本物だよ わかってんだろうけどな
I think you know that.
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Honestly,
僕としちゃあ
I'd prefer if you didn't hang out with Hanekawa.
正直 お前らに羽川と付き合って欲しいとは思わないんだけどな
But I guess this is a good chance.
いい機会だ
これからは あいつから色々と学べ
From now on, you should start learning from her.
動くな 拭きづらい
Don't move.
It's hard to wipe you down.
もういいよ 大分すっきりした
It's fine now. I feel much better.
We're almost done. Don't stop now.
ここまできて遠慮すんなよ
兄ちゃんに病気移しちまってもつまんねえ
I don't want to get you sick.
Get me sick?
ん 移す
ちょ ちょっと待ってろ
Wait a second.
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Shinobu.
忍
What?
なんじゃい
わしはそろそろ眠る時間なんじゃがの
It's almost time for bed.
ああ じゃあ おねむの前にひとつだけ
Then, one thing before bed...
Is there any way to transfer her illness to me?
あいつの病気を僕に移す方法ってないのか
病気っつっても根本的には怪異の毒だ
It's more of a supernatural poison than an illness.
それに そもそも意図的に移されたものだ
And it was given to her deliberately.
だったら その毒を更に
So wouldn't it be possible for her to give it to me?
僕に移し変えることもできるんじゃないのか
So you're saying you'll take her illness?
病をお前様が背負おうと
There is a way.
あるはある
しかし わしとしては 正直勧められん方法じゃな
But honestly, I can't recommend it.
勧められんと言うか
Or it would be more accurate to say
I certainly wouldn't prefer it.
その 酷く気の進まん方法じゃ
I understand there's a risk.
リスクは承知だ
I don't know if "risk" is the right word.
リスクと言うかのう
まあ それはそれで都市伝説なのじゃが
Well, I suppose it's an urban legend.
確か あの小僧はまったく違う文脈で言っておったような
I think the kid described it in a completely different way.
What?
なんだよ 煮えない言い方だな
That's pretty vague. And not like you at all.
お前らしくもない
どうじゃろうなあ
Well, I don't know...
許されることなのかどうなのか
Whether it's something that would be allowed or not, I couldn't say.
わしとしては判断しかねる
なんだか知らないが
I don't know what you're talking about,
許されるに決まってるだろ
but of course it would.
あいつの苦しみを癒す方法があるんなら
If there's any way to alleviate her suffering,
それが何であれ 実行するべきだ
we should take it.
Very true.
至極その通り じゃな
ならば 好きにするがよい
Do what you will.
Nii-chan,
兄ちゃん トイレかなんか知らないけれど
I don't know if you went to the bathroom or what,
but you should have at least dressed me first.
行くなら服着せてから行ってくれよ
Karen-chan.
火憐ちゃん
I'm going to kiss you now.
今からお前とキスするぞ
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
'Sup! I'm Karen!
We're the fire sisters!
I don't like the thought of being alone.
I think we've all caught a cold before,
but don't you think the characters used to write it are a bit peculiar?
I'm so whimsical.
I feel like I don't stand out much...
That's not true.
The wind character is read like that on its own, so what's 'malice' doing after it?
Isn't the 'malice' unneeded? Wouldn't it be read the same without it?
To make the most of my
strong points,
I'll go learn under a karate master.
What bringing this on?
I know I'm being fussy here,
and maybe they just wanted to make sure there's a difference between just wind and cold,
which are both pronounced the same,
but why didn't they just change what they called the common cold?
Roar
Waterfall
Bear
Grr~
Mountain
I was too naive!
It's going to air soon!
And isn't the on'yomi reading 'fuuja' anyway?
Oh, fuuja!
Whoah, that sounds so cool and mysterious.
I'll shave off one
eyebrow and get
myself
psyched up!
What!
Razor!
Final and ultimate secret of the Araragi school of self-defense!
Fuuja!
Next time! Karen Bee, Part 6!
Next Time
Karen Bee Part 6
That reminds me, summer cold and summer wind also sound the same, don't they?
We're the whimsical sisters!